DAVID CORNISH

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

CONTACT

- 615.939.1934
- □ dcornish84@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/david-L-cornish
- github.com/dcornish84

ABOUT ME

My path to software development has been long and winding. I became interested in pursuing this career after meeting so many happy developers out in the world and learning about the intersection of the analytical and the creative in development. Suddenly my seemingly unrelated professional experiences didn't look so random. Music Row taught me how to collaborate in a creative environment, learn and incorporate new technology quickly, and persevere to finish projects. At Cumberland Heights I learned how to work with all different kinds of people, analyze data sets, and live outside my comfort zone. The Omni trained me up in hospitality and business so I got the macro view of operations without diminishing the importance of customer service. Development has been a welcome addition to these experiences. Getting lost in code, working closely with a team, learning new languages - it's all so new but familiar at the same time. I'm so excited to see where it will lead.

PERSONAL PROJECT

RecordCollector. A web application built in React used to compile album information in a catalogue and wishlist format. I built this application to help manage my vinyl collection. Utilizing the Discogs API I was able to acquire album information and then save it to a catalogue or wishlist JSON database with full CRUD functionality. Additional technology used includes JSX, CSS, and Reactstrap.

EDUCATION

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING
NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

AUDIO TECHNOLOGY
SAE INSTITUTE NASHVILLE

BACHELOR OF ARTS, PSYCHOLOGY UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL SIX MONTH FULL STACK BOOTCAMP

AUG 2019 - FEB 2020

- Source code version control with Git/GitHub and project tracking with Github Projects
- JavaScript fundamentals using DRY, modular, readable code and reusable components
- React, HTML, CSS built browser-based single-page applications
- Hands on application of Object Oriented Programming fundamentals
- Group and individual projects reflecting real world team dynamics and problem solving
- Experience using Bootstrap and Reactstrap to style web applications

Group Projects

NUTSHELL

- Collaborated with 2 teammates to create a single-page social platform that allowed users to organize news articles, events, tasks, and chat with other users
- Utilized React JS and JSON server for persistent data storage
- Implemented user-specific CRUD functionality for the task module

C#/.Net

Bangazon Workforce Management: ASP.NET and MVC internal web app for HR and IT to manage resources. Responsible for creating the Training Programs controller with full CRUD.
 Bangazon Web API: Exposed resources from server to app developers of e-commerce store. Role included creating models/controllers with CRUD functionality for "Departments" and "Computers" resources and writing integration tests.

OMNI HOTELS AND RESORTS

F&B MANAGER

JUL 2016 - JUL 2019

- Improved efficiency in inventory, labor and point-of-sale management using Oracle MICROS
- Supervised the ordering of product, inventory control, and merchandising
- Conducted service and product training

CUMBERLAND HEIGHTS TREATMENT CENTER

QUALITY MANAGEMENT SPECIALIST

JUN 2015 - JUL 2016

- Completed data analysis using Excel to compile monthly breakdowns of Patient Satisfaction Surveys, Incident Reports, Metrics, and Chart Audits to discover trends and formulate action plans for improving services
- Maintained and updated Policies and Procedures for the entire facility
- Inspected treatment inpatient and outpatient facilities to ensure state compliance

CLINICAL ASSOCIATE

JAN 2014 - JUN 2015

- Conducted 16 educational and experiential therapy groups in the Men's Center a month
- State certified Ropes Course Instructor, utilizing certification in several experiential groups and high ropes activities
- Utilized de-escalation techniques to ensure the well being of patients and staff

16TH EDGE STUDIOS

AUDIO ENGINEER

MAY 2011 - MAR 2014

• Utilized ProTools, UAD plugins, Logic, outboard gear such as LA2A and 1176 compressors to record, edit, and mix tracks. Booked clients, maintained gear.